

Profile

Software engineering manager always looking for self-improvement, with 2+ years of engineer management experience and 9+ years of software development experience. Dedicated to leveling up engineers and guiding a project to success with my experience in full development life-cycles across several mobile games, and collaborating with other disciplines.

Employment History

Engineering Manager at Zynga, Toronto

January 2019 — Present

Hands-on management with 5 software engineers over 2 mobile game teams:

- Recruiting and leveling up the team; providing paths for career growth
- Hands-on in full development life-cycle
- · Tech scoping and planning
- Identifying issues in and improving: team process, game pipelines and tech stack
- Collaborating efforts across other teams and disciplines

Senior Software Engineer at Zynga, Toronto

July 2013 — December 2018

Working in agile-like processes to ship game client updates for several mobile game projects

- Full development life-cycle: design, implementation, testing, release & support
- Worked within various tech stacks including legacy code bases
- Coordinating feature experimentation and player analytics
- · Reacting to game metrics and app health analysis
- · Working with product management to realize their vision
- · Recruiting and mentoring interns

Software Engineer at Zynga, Toronto

July 2011 — June 2013

Working under senior staff direction across a few mobile game projects

- Feature implementation
- Feature iterations
- Bug fixes and patches

Projects

Boggle with Friends (Android/iOS)

- Online, turn-based word game
- Title maintenance: New features and game updates
- Licensed IP re-brand (previously titled Word Streak with Friends and Scramble with Friends)
- Tech involved: Java, Kotlin, Objective-C, Swift, ReactiveX, Retrofit, Alamofire, AndEngine, Cocos2d-objc, SQLite

Details

Mississauga, Canada, +1 (647)-823-8395 howling.ape@gmail.com

Skills

Android Development

iOS Development

Unity

GitHub

Jenkins

Java

Kotlin

Objective-C

Swift

C#

JavaScript

Ruby

ReactiveX

Hobbies

Karate, Sumo, Longboarding, Gaming, Music Production

Mafia Wars (Android/iOS)

- MMO base building PvP game
- New title (sunset after beta)
- Client implementation of social features
- Tech involved: Unity (C#)

Chess with Friends (Android/iOS)

- Online, multiplayer version of Chess
- Title maintenance: New features and game updates
- Tech involved: Java, Objective-C, JavaScript, NDK, Cocos2d-js, SQLite

Trivia Prototype (Mobile, unreleased)

- Fast prototyping of a multiplayer trivia game
- Tech involved: Java, libGDX, SQLite, Firebase

Draw Something 2 (Android)

- Instagram inspired, online, turn-based drawing game
- New title, worldwide launched
- Tech involved: Java, NDK, Cocos2d-x

Dream Zoo (Android)

- Zoo simulation game
- New title, worldwide launched
- Tech involved: Java, AndEngine

Education

Computer Science with Software Engineering Option, University of Waterloo, Waterloo

September 2006 — April 2011

◄ References

References available upon request